Shaswata Das

+880-1748-479050 · <u>shaswata56@gmail.com</u>

• github.com/shaswata56 • linkedin.com/in/shaswata56

H-1, R-1, Kaderabad Housing, Mohammadpur, Dhaka.

SUMMARY STATEMENT

I am a fast-learning, creative individual with a research-driven approach. I aim to prove my value and talent in a disruptive tech company, advance my skills through mentorship, and tackle any challenge with confidence. My expertise in computer science spans across networking, cloud, IoT, web, distributed systems, and AI.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Orbitax Bangladesh Limited Associate Software Engineer

Mar 2022 - Present

During this time, I focused on enhancing the functionality of the system by implementing essential business logic. Additionally, I developed a few important features to improve the overall user experience. To ensure optimal performance, I made significant improvements to the administration and security. Lastly, I worked diligently to identify and squash critical bugs that were impacting system stability and reliability.

Orbitax Bangladesh Limited

Sep 2021 - Feb 2022

Software Engineer Intern

Ported an existing .NET microservices in Go for R&D purposes, which decreased response latency by 60% and reduced memory usage by 70%.

It's FOSS Dec 2020 - Feb 2021

Tech Journalist

Covered important news about the Free and Open-Source Software community.

EDUCATION

Shahjalal University of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Engineering in Software Engineering CGPA - 3.34 (160 credit)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Cloud Engineering with Google Cloud
- Blockchain by the University at Buffalo
- Deep Learning by DeepLearning.AI
- Penetration Testing and Ethical Hacking by Cybrary
- DFIR by <u>BASISTECH LLC</u>

SKILLS

- Highly creative, critical thinking and debugging skills and excellent written and verbal communication skills
- Strong leadership skills and ability to communicate with stakeholders of different backgrounds and skill levels
- Professional experience with ASP .NET Core and MVC framework using Razor page
- Highly experienced with Linux/UNIX
- Highly proficient in scripting using Bash Shell, PowerShell and Python
- Experienced with ML and AI (CNN, RNN, LLM, GAN)
- Experienced with SQL and NoSQL
- Experienced with GCP, AWS and Azure
- Experience of backend development using Go, Java, .NET and Python
- Experience of Blockchain (Ethereum-Solidity)
- Professional experience of frontend development using Angular, Bootstrap
- Experienced in both offensive and defensive information security